<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Word>
    <Item>
        <ID>1</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Priest</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/priːst/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>linh mục</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Vị linh mục Phải RÍT Sâu 1 hơi để lấy bình tĩnh</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a person who is qualified to perform religious duties and ceremonies in the Roman Catholic, Anglican and Orthodox Churches</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>The priest welcomed is as we entered the church</Eg>
        <Dich>Vị linh mục được chào đón khi chúng tôi bước vào nhà thờ</Dich>
        <Srcimg>priest</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>2</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Generally</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈdʒenrəli/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>Nhìn chung</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Nhìn chung thì JEN NÓ GIỜ LÌ lợm lắm</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>by or to most people</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Generally, Vietnamese people wake up quite earlty</Eg>
        <Dich>Nhìn chung, người Việt Nam dậy khá sớm</Dich>
        <Srcimg>generally</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>3</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Celebration</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˌselɪˈbreɪʃn/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>ăn mừng</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Vì ăn mừng qua khích nên khi sơn XE, LƠ Bị DÂY SƠN ra áo</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a special event that people organize in order to celebrate something</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>We held a celebration for his graduation</Eg>
        <Dich>Chúng tôi tổ chức lễ kỷ niệm ngày tốt nghiệp của anh ấy</Dich>
        <Srcimg>celebration</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>4</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Pray</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/preɪ/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>cầu nguyện</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Cầu nguyện xin tội lỗi nay hóa Bột, RÂY ra thôi phát bay hết</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>to speak to God, especially to give thanks or ask for help</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>The coach prays by himself before entering the football match</Eg>
        <Dich>The coach prays by himself before entering the foodball match</Dich>
        <Srcimg>pray</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>5</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Party</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈpɑːrti/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>tiệc</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Bọn tui tiệc tùng ở nhà PÁ TI, em thống lý Pá Tra</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a social occasion, often in a person’s home, at which people eat, drink, talk, dance and enjoy themselves</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>I dont Generally like to Party, Expect in my birthdays</Eg>
        <Dich>Nói chung tôi không thích Tiệc tùng, mong đợi trong ngày sinh nhật của mình</Dich>
        <Srcimg>party</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>6</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Wedding</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈwedɪŋ/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>lễ cưới</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Sau lễ cưới,Vy thề sẽ càn QUÉT DING tea.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a marriage ceremony, and the meal or party that usually follows it</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>I've been to five weddings this month, so I'm almost broke</Eg>
        <Dich>Tôi đã dự năm đám cưới trong tháng này, vì vậy tôi gần như đã phá vỡ</Dich>
        <Srcimg>wedding</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>7</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Occasion</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/əˈkeɪʒn/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>dịp đặc biệt</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Ơ! CÂY DẦN mua sáng nay cho dịp đặc biệt gì đấy</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a particular time when something happens</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>She obviously dressed up for this Occasion</Eg>
        <Dich>Cô ấy rõ ràng là mặc đồ cho dịp này</Dich>
        <Srcimg>occasion</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>8</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Relative</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈrelətɪv/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>họ hàng</Nghia>
        <YNghia>các bác họ hàng im RE, LƠ TIẾP chuyện vì đang bận</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>considered and judged by being compared with something else</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>They invited every relative in my family, even some I didnt know.</Eg>
        <Dich>Họ mời mọi người thân trong gia đình tôi, thậm chí một số tôi không biết.</Dich>
        <Srcimg>relative</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>9</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Guest</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ɡest/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>khách</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Cu tí GHÉT Sơn chải chuốt mỗi khi có khách</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a person that you have invited to your house or to a particular event that you are paying for</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Go say hello to your guest</Eg>
        <Dich>Đi chào khách của bạn</Dich>
        <Srcimg>guest</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>10</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Festival</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈfestɪvl/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>lễ hội</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Đừng bốc PHÉT, TÍ VỒ lấy Vy ở lễ hội hồi nào?</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a series of public events connected with a particular activity or idea</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Let's go to the book Festival at the park!</Eg>
        <Dich>Cùng đi dự Hội sách ở công viên nhé!</Dich>
        <Srcimg>festival</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>11</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Firework</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈfaɪərwɜːrk/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>pháo hoa</Nghia>
        <YNghia>PHẢI Ở QUỐC gia nào mới được xem pháo hoa chống ồn đây?</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a small device containing powder that burns or explodes and produces bright coloured lights and loud noises, used especially at celebrations</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>There's going to be a firework display tonight at HoanKiem lake</Eg>
        <Dich>Tối nay có bắn pháo hoa ở hồ HoanKiem</Dich>
        <Srcimg>firework</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>12</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Ceremony</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈserəməʊni/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>buổi lễ</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Trước buổi lễ mà mơ XE RỈ, MƠ NI-lông là có nghĩa gì?</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a public or religious occasion that includes a series of formal or traditional actions</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>The women wore traditional outfits for the Ceremony</Eg>
        <Dich>Những người phụ nữ mặc trang phục truyền thống cho buổi lễ</Dich>
        <Srcimg>ceremony</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>13</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Offering</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈɔːfərɪŋ/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>lễ vật</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Lễ vật là cua ÓP, PHỞ, RINH quà ngay kẻo hết</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>something that is produced for other people to use, watch, enjoy, etc.</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>In the past, people used to make Offering to the gods</Eg>
        <Dich>Trước đây, người ta thường cúng dường các vị thần.</Dich>
        <Srcimg>offering</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>14</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Welcome</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈwelkəm/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>hoan nghênh</Nghia>
        <YNghia>EO,CĂM thù nhau đến mấy vẫn nên vỗ tay hoan nghênh chứ</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>used as a greeting to tell somebody that you are pleased that they are there</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Staff were at the gate to welcome visitors</Eg>
        <Dich>Nhân viên túc trực ở cổng chào đón du khách</Dich>
        <Srcimg>welcome</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>15</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Luck</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/lʌk/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>vận may</Nghia>
        <YNghia>LẮC cả 2 tay, vận may sẽ đến</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>good things that happen to you by chance, not because of your own efforts or abilities</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>SHe chose the colour red because it brings luck</Eg>
        <Dich>SHe chọn màu đỏ vì nó mang lại may mắn</Dich>
        <Srcimg>luck</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>16</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Holiday</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈhɑːlədeɪ/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>ngày lễ</Nghia>
        <YNghia>ê HÀ, LƠ ĐÂY! ngày lễ tết rổi đi chơi thôi!</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a period of time when you are not at work or school</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Tet is the most important holiday in VN</Eg>
        <Dich>Tết là ngày lễ quan trọng nhất ở Việt Nam</Dich>
        <Srcimg>holiday</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>17</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>National</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈnæʃnəl/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>toàn quốc</Nghia>
        <YNghia>NA SỪNg sộ NỔ bỏng ăn mừng ngày quốc tế độc thân toàn quốc</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>connected with a particular nation; shared by a whole nation</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Most companies dont work on national holidays</Eg>
        <Dich>Hầu hết các công ty không làm việc vào các ngày lễ quốc gia</Dich>
        <Srcimg>national</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>18</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Congratulations</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/kənˈɡræts/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>chúc mừng</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Mai kệ CƠN Gió RÉT, CHỜ LẤY SƯỜN về làm tiệc chúc mừng năm mới.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a message congratulating somebody</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Congratulations! you will be amazing parents!</Eg>
        <Dich>Xin chúc mừng! bạn sẽ là những bậc cha mẹ tuyệt vời!</Dich>
        <Srcimg>congratulations</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>19</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Tidy</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈtaɪdi/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>dọn dẹp</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Miếng thịt này THÁI ĐI rồi dọn dẹp bếp sạch sẽ nhé!.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>arranged neatly and with everything in order</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>It usually takes several days to tidy the house before the new year</Eg>
        <Dich>Thường mất vài ngày để dọn dẹp nhà cửa trước năm mới</Dich>
        <Srcimg>tidy</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>20</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Exchange</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ɪksˈtʃeɪndʒ/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>Trao đổi</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Trao đổi lợi ÍCH TRÊN mạng bằng việc thả tim bài nhau.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>an act of giving something to somebody or doing something for somebody and receiving something in return</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Where can I exchange VND to USD?</Eg>
        <Dich>Tôi có thể đổi từ VND sang USD ở đâu?</Dich>
        <Srcimg>exchange</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>21</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Public</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈpʌblɪk/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>công chúng</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Hotgirl Trang BẮP LÍCH kích xách váy cúi chào công chúng.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>connected with ordinary people in society in general</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>THe public seem very interesting in the most recent scandal</Eg>
        <Dich>Công chúng có vẻ rất thú vị trong vụ bê bối gần đây nhất</Dich>
        <Srcimg>public1</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>22</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Anniversary</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˌænɪˈvɜːrsəri/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>ngày kỉ niệm</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Tặng EM NY VỚ SƠ-RI vào ngày kỉ niệm 5 năm.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a date that is an exact number of years after the date of an important or special event</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>i took my wife to dinner on our Anniversary</Eg>
        <Dich>tôi đã đưa vợ tôi đi ăn tối vào ngày kỷ niệm của chúng tôi</Dich>
        <Srcimg>anniversary</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>23</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Lantern</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈlæntərn/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>đèn lồng</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Mai làm đèn lồng LÉN TỪNg ngày để bán kiếm tiền.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a lamp in a clear case, often a metal case with glass sides, and often with a handle, so that you can carry it outside</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>HoiAn is so dreamy with the streets lit up using lantern</Eg>
        <Dich>HoiAn thơ mộng với những con đường thắp sáng đèn lồng</Dich>
        <Srcimg>lantern</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>24</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Peace</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/piːs/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>sự bình yên</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Muốn đi xe trong sự bình yên thì phải sửa PIS-tông.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a situation or a period of time in which there is no war or violence in a country or an area</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>people typically have to leave the city in order to find some peace</Eg>
        <Dich>mọi người thường phải rời thành phố để tìm một chút bình yên</Dich>
        <Srcimg>peace</Srcimg>
    </Item>

</Word>

