<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Word>
    <Item>
        <ID>1</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Fishing</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈfɪʃɪŋ/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>câu cá</Nghia>
        <YNghia>ông chủ thu PHÍ SÌNH lầy để mọi người vào câu cá</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>the sport or business of catching fish</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>His favorite thing to do in his free time is to go Fishing</Eg>
        <Dich>Việc anh ấy thích làm trong thời gian rảnh là đi câu cá</Dich>
        <Srcimg>fishing</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>2</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Coast</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/kəʊst/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>bờ biển</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Hãy ra bờ biển lấy dừa làm nước CỐT</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>enlarge imagethe land next to or near to the sea or ocean</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>PhuQuoc isn't very far from the coast of Vietnam</Eg>
        <Dich>PhuQuoc không xa bờ biển Việt Nam</Dich>
        <Srcimg>coast</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>3</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Surround</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/səˈraʊnd/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>bao quanh</Nghia>
        <YNghia>SƠ RAO truyền tình yêu bằng việc trông hoa bao quanh nhà thờ</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>to be all around something/somebody</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>High walls Surround the imperial citadel of thang long</Eg>
        <Dich>Tường cao Bao quanh hoàng thành Thăng Long</Dich>
        <Srcimg>surround</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>4</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Gorgeous</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈɡɔːrdʒəs/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>tuyệt đẹp</Nghia>
        <YNghia>cuộc chiến cam GO RƯỢT đuổi quanh tòa nhà tuyệt đẹp</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>very beautiful and attractive; giving great pleasure</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>he scenery in HaGiang is absolutely Gorgeous</Eg>
        <Dich>anh ấy phong cảnh ở HaGiang là hoàn toàn tuyệt đẹp</Dich>
        <Srcimg>gorgeous</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>5</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Scenery</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈsiːnəri/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>Phong cảnh</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Phong cảnh nơi đây XIN NHỜ DÌ chăm sóc</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>the natural features of an area, such as mountains, valleys, rivers and forests, when you are thinking about them being attractive to look at</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>The scenery in the movie KING KONG helped make NinhBinh famous</Eg>
        <Dich>Khung cảnh trong phim VUA KỲ DIỆU đã giúp Ninh Bình trở nên nổi tiếng</Dich>
        <Srcimg>scenery</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>6</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Island</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈaɪlənd/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>hòn đảo</Nghia>
        <YNghia>AI LỪNG danh trên hòn đảo này cũng cực kỳ nguy hiểm</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a piece of land that is completely surrounded by water</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Singapore is an island, as well as a city and a country</Eg>
        <Dich>Singapore là một hòn đảo, cũng như một thành phố và một quốc gia</Dich>
        <Srcimg>island</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>7</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Map</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/mæp/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>bản đồ</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Mai dùng ngón tay mũm mĩm mập MẠP vẽ bản đồ</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a drawing or plan of the earth’s surface or part of it, showing countries, towns, rivers, etc.</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>everyone should learn how to use a map to travel</Eg>
        <Dich>mọi người nên học cách sử dụng bản đồ để đi du lịch</Dich>
        <Srcimg>map</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>8</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Mountain</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈmaʊntn/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>núi</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Tam MAO TỪNG lên núi, xuống biển để tìm mẹ</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a very high hill, often with rocks near the top</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Fansipan is the highest mountain in VN</Eg>
        <Dich>Fansipan là đỉnh núi cao nhất Việt Nam</Dich>
        <Srcimg>mountain</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>9</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Bay</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/beɪ/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>vịnh</Nghia>
        <YNghia>đức hỏi:"tụi BÂY đã bao giờ đi vịnh hạ long chưa?"</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a part of the sea, or of a large lake, partly surrounded by a wide curve of the land</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>There aremany beautiful places in VN, besides HALONG Bay</Eg>
        <Dich>Có rất nhiều địa điểm đẹp ở VN, ngoài Vịnh HALONG</Dich>
        <Srcimg>bay</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>10</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Lake</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/leɪk/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>hồ</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Tuấn mệt mỏi LẾCH đi về phía hồ</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a large area of water that is surrounded by land</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>the old women played loud music and did aerobics next to the lake</Eg>
        <Dich>những người phụ nữ lớn tuổi bật nhạc lớn và tập thể dục nhịp điệu cạnh hồ</Dich>
        <Srcimg>lake</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>11</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Waterfall</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈwɔːtərfɔːl/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>thác nước</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Water + fall= nước + rơi= thác nước</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a place where a stream or river falls from a high place, for example over a cliff or rock</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>The elephant Waterfall in dalat is a famous tourist attraction</Eg>
        <Dich>Thác voi ở Dalat là một điểm thu hút khách du lịch nổi tiếng</Dich>
        <Srcimg>waterfall</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>12</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Forest</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈfɔːrɪst/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>rừng</Nghia>
        <YNghia>anh đội PHÓ HÉT to báo hiệu khu rừng đang cháy</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a large area of land that is thickly covered with trees</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Many ethnic minorities live areas surrounded by forest.</Eg>
        <Dich>Nhiều dân tộc thiểu số sống trong các khu vực được bao quanh bởi rừng</Dich>
        <Srcimg>forest</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>13</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Rough</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/rʌf/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>gồ gề</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Luôn có người RẮP tâm hãm hại trên đường gồ gề ta đi</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>having a surface that is not even or regular</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>The Rough roads are hard to drive on</Eg>
        <Dich>Đường gồ ghề khó lái xe</Dich>
        <Srcimg>rough</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>14</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Cave</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/keɪv/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>hang</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Mai ngồi ăn bánh kếp trong hang động</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>enlarge imagea large hole in the side of a hill or cliff or under the ground</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Son Doong is the largest cave in the world</Eg>
        <Dich>Sơn Đoòng là hang động lớn nhất thế giới</Dich>
        <Srcimg>cave</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>15</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Icy</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈaɪsi/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>băng</Nghia>
        <YNghia>AI XÌ hơi ở nơi băng giá thế này?</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>very cold</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>They cling to a board in the icy water and watch the Titanic sink</Eg>
        <Dich>Họ bám vào một tấm ván trong làn nước băng giá và xem tàu Titanic chìm</Dich>
        <Srcimg>icy</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>16</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Lighter</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈlaɪtər/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>bật lửa</Nghia>
        <YNghia>trong tương LAI,TỜ giấy sẽ đốt lại bật lửa</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a small device that produces a flame for lighting cigarettes, etc.</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>he couldn't start a campfire using just a Lighter</Eg>
        <Dich>anh ấy không thể bắt đầu đốt lửa trại chỉ bằng Bật lửa</Dich>
        <Srcimg>lighter</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>17</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Spider</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈspaɪdər/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>nhện</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Con nhện vẫn luôn giăng tơ SUỐT BAO ĐỜI nay</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a small creature with eight thin legs. Many spiders spin webs to catch insects for food.</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Spider make webs to catch bugs</Eg>
        <Dich>Nhện tạo mạng để bắt bọ</Dich>
        <Srcimg>spider</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>18</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Surprisingly</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/sərˈpraɪzɪŋli/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>bất ngờ</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Bà SƠ PHẢI DÍNH LY vào bàn vì sợ vỡ một cách bất ngờ.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>in a way that causes surprise</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>VN has gorwn Surprisingly quickly</Eg>
        <Dich>VN đã sinh sôi nảy nở nhanh chóng một cách đáng ngạc nhiên</Dich>
        <Srcimg>surprisingly</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>19</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>sunbathe</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈsʌnbeɪð/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>tắm nắng</Nghia>
        <YNghia>sun + bathe= mặt trời + tắm= tắm nắng.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>to sit or lie in the sun, especially in order to go brown </TiengAnh>
        <Eg>people in VN don't often sunbathe, as they prefer having white skin</Eg>
        <Dich>người dân Việt Nam không thường xuyên tắm nắng vì họ thích có làn da trắng hơn</Dich>
        <Srcimg>sunbathe</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>20</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Wonder</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈwʌndər/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>kì quan</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Người phụ nữ đi kêu OAN ĐỜ đẫn đứng ngắm kì quan.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>to think about something and try to decide what is true, what will happen, what you should do, etc.</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>The great wall of china is one of the great wonders of the world</Eg>
        <Dich>Bức tường thành vĩ đại của Trung Quốc là một trong những kỳ quan vĩ đại của thế giới</Dich>
        <Srcimg>wonder</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>21</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Wildlife</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈwaɪldlaɪf/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>động vật hoang dã</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Wild + life= hoang dã + sự sống= đv hoang dã.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>animals, birds, insects, etc. that are wild and live in a natural environment</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>there isn't much Wildlife is areas around the city</Eg>
        <Dich>không có nhiều Động vật hoang dã xung quanh thành phố</Dich>
        <Srcimg>wildlife</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>22</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Sanctuary</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈsæŋktʃueri/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>khu bảo tồn</Nghia>
        <YNghia>mây XANH,TRỜI RÌ rầm tiếng chim tron gkhu bảo tồn.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>an area where wild birds or animals are protected and encouraged to produce young</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>the ThungNham bird garden is a sanctuary for bird</Eg>
        <Dich>vườn chim ThungNham là khu bảo tồn chim</Dich>
        <Srcimg>sanctuary</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>23</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Bamboo</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˌbæmˈbuː/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>cây tre</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Đê lấy phần thưởng phía trên , học BÈN BU quanh để lao cây tre.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a tall plant that is a member of the grass family and has hard hollow stems that are used for making furniture, poles, etc.</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>The table was made of bamboo, so it was light, cheap, and strong</Eg>
        <Dich>Cái bàn làm bằng tre nên nhẹ, rẻ và chắc</Dich>
        <Srcimg>bamboo</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>24</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Cliff</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/klɪf/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>vách đá</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Cụ LÝ PHờ phạc sau khi chinh phục được vách đá.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>enlarge image a high area of rock with a very steep side, often at the edge of the sea or ocean</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>The cliffs at the HaiVan pass are very dangerous</Eg>
        <Dich>Các vách đá ở đèo Hải Vân rất hiểm trở</Dich>
        <Srcimg>cliff</Srcimg>
    </Item>

</Word>

