<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Word>
    <Item>
        <ID>1</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>buffalo</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈbʌfələʊ/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>con trâu</Nghia>
        <YNghia>con trâu ném BẮP PHÁ LẦU trên của ngôi nhà</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a large animal of the cow family that has wide, curved horns.</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Have you ever ridden a buffalo</Eg>
        <Dich>Bạn đã từng cưỡi trâu chưa</Dich>
        <Srcimg>buffalo</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>2</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Range</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/reɪndʒ/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>dãy</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Dãy núi như đang RÊN rỉ khi nhìn thấy cây bị chặt</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a variety of things of a particular type</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Sapa is beautiful with mountain Range covered in clouds</Eg>
        <Dich>Sapa tuyệt đẹp với những dãy núi bao phủ trong mây</Dich>
        <Srcimg>range</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>3</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>steep</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/stiːp/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>dốc</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Sao TÍP người béo lại không thích leo đèo dốc</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>rising or falling quickly, not graduall</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>It is dangerous to ride a bicycle down a steep road</Eg>
        <Dich>Đi xe đạp xuống đường dốc rất nguy hiểm</Dich>
        <Srcimg>steep</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>4</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Explore</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ɪkˈsplɔːr/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>khám phá</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Con ẾCH LO nó không còn sức đi khám phá xung quanh</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>to travel to or around an area or a country in order to learn about it</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>I can't wait to go Explore Cuc Phuognw National Park</Eg>
        <Dich>Tôi nóng lòng muốn đi Khám phá Vườn Quốc gia Cuc Phuognw</Dich>
        <Srcimg>explore</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>5</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Leisurely</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈliːʒərli/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>thong thả</Nghia>
        <YNghia>mai LÉ GIỜ LY hôn rồi nên đi chơi một cách thong thả</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>done without hurrying</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>We drove Leisurely so we could relax and see the sights</Eg>
        <Dich>Chúng tôi lái xe nhàn nhã để có thể thư giãn và ngắm nhìn các thắng cảnh</Dich>
        <Srcimg>leisurely</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>6</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Custom</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈkʌstəm/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>phong tục</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Chắc CHỚT! TỪNG này phong tục thi sao nhớ nổi</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>an accepted way of behaving or of doing things in a society or a community</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>It's best to follow local customs when tralvelling</Eg>
        <Dich>Tốt nhất bạn nên tuân theo phong tục địa phương khi đi phượt</Dich>
        <Srcimg>custom</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>7</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Permission</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/pərˈmɪʃn/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>cho phép</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Bán bơ, mít, sừng trâu cần có sự cho phép</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>the act of allowing somebody to do something, especially when this is done by somebody in a position of authority</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>You need the teacher's Permission before leaving the class</Eg>
        <Dich>Bạn cần có sự cho phép của giáo viên trước khi rời khỏi lớp học</Dich>
        <Srcimg>permission</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>8</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Grow</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ɡrəʊ/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>lớn lên</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Lớn lên đàn ông thườnG RÂU ria xồm xoàm</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>to increase in size, number, strength or quality</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>It doesn't take long for children to grow</Eg>
        <Dich>Không mất nhiều thời gian để trẻ lớn lên</Dich>
        <Srcimg>grow</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>9</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Quiet</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈkwaɪət/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>yên tĩnh</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Con yêu QUÁI chỢT thôi phá phách đề tìm nơi yên tĩnh</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>making very little noise</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Down my alley, it's very quite, as it's far from main roads</Eg>
        <Dich>Dưới con hẻm của tôi, nó rất khá, vì nó cách xa các con đường chính</Dich>
        <Srcimg>quiet</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>10</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Neighbour</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈneɪbər/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>hàng xóm</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Mấy nhà hàng xóm ai NẤY BỜ rào cũng cao chót vót</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a person who lives next to you or near you</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>I often gossip with my Neighbour when I see him</Eg>
        <Dich>Tôi thường nói chuyện phiếm với Hàng xóm của mình khi tôi gặp anh ấy</Dich>
        <Srcimg>neighbour</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>11</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>dangerous</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈdeɪndʒərəs/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>nguy hiểm</Nghia>
        <YNghia>ĐẾN GIỜ RƯỢT đuổi của bọn trộm cắp rồi, nguy hiểm quá</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>likely to injure or harm somebody, or to damage or destroy something</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>It's dangerous to go mountain climbing alone</Eg>
        <Dich>Đi leo núi một mình rất nguy hiểm</Dich>
        <Srcimg>dangerous</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>12</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Part</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/pɑːrt/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>phần</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Chiếc BÁT nhỏ chỉ chứa đucợ 1 phần cơm</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>part of something some but not all of a thing</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>We only complated a part of the assignment</Eg>
        <Dich>Chúng tôi chỉ hoàn thành một phần nhiệm vụ</Dich>
        <Srcimg>part</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>13</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Bug</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/bʌɡ/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>bọ</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Gió BẤC thổi bây mấy con bọ</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>any small insect</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>I found a bug on my bathroom floor!</Eg>
        <Dich>Tôi tìm thấy một con bọ trên sàn phòng tắm của mình!</Dich>
        <Srcimg>bug</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>14</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Brave</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/breɪv/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>dũng cảm</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Tuấn dũng cảm Bắt RẾT hộ vy</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>willing to do things that are difficult, dangerous or painful; not afraid</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>You must be so brave to cross the street in Saigon</Eg>
        <Dich>Bạn phải rất dũng cảm để băng qua đường ở Sài Gòn</Dich>
        <Srcimg>brave</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>15</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Protect</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/prəˈtekt/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>bảo vệ</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Để bảo vệ mái tóc, Mai dùng BỜM RỒI TẾT tóc lại</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>to make sure that somebody/something is not harmed, injured, damaged, etc.</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>I wear a helmet to Protect my beautiful face</Eg>
        <Dich>Tôi đội mũ bảo hiểm để bảo vệ khuôn mặt xinh đẹp của mình</Dich>
        <Srcimg>protect</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>16</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Architecture</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈɑːrkɪtektʃər/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>kiến trúc</Nghia>
        <YNghia>A KÌA TẠCH TRƯỜNG kiến trúc mất rồi</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>the art and study of designing buildings</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>The Architecture in the French quarter looks like it's from long ago</Eg>
        <Dich>Kiến trúc trong khu phố Pháp trông giống như nó đã có từ lâu</Dich>
        <Srcimg>architecture</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>17</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Rainforest</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈreɪnfɔːrɪst/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>rừng chiệt đới</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Rain+ Forest= mưa + rừng=  rừng nhiều mưa= rừng nhiệt đới </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a thick forest in tropical parts of the world that have a lot of rain</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Rainforest are the lungs of the Earth</Eg>
        <Dich>Rừng nhiệt đới là lá phổi của Trái đất</Dich>
        <Srcimg>rainforest</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>18</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Handicraft</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈhændikræft/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>nghề thủ công</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Hand + craft= tay + thủ công= nghề thủ công.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>the activity of making attractive objects by hand</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Bat Trang is a Handicraft village where people still make items by hand</Eg>
        <Dich>Bát Tràng là một làng nghề thủ công, nơi mọi người vẫn làm các vật dụng bằng tay</Dich>
        <Srcimg>handicraft</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>19</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Satisfied</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈsætɪsfaɪd/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>hài lòng</Nghia>
        <YNghia>muốn khách hài lòng thì XÉ THỊT PHẢI thật nhỏ.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>pleased because you have achieved something or because something that you wanted to happen has happened</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>After hours of working hard, she was finally Satisfied with the assay</Eg>
        <Dich>Sau nhiều giờ làm việc chăm chỉ, cuối cùng cô ấy cũng hài lòng với thử nghiệm</Dich>
        <Srcimg>satisfied</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>20</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Rely</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/rɪˈlaɪ/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>dựa dẫm</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Cây sơ-RI LAI cà chua kia dựa dẫm vào nắng để sống.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh></TiengAnh>
        <Eg>She doesn't want to worl. so she chose to rely on her boyfriend instead</Eg>
        <Dich>Cô ấy không muốn làm việc. vì vậy cô ấy chọn dựa vào bạn trai của mình thay vì</Dich>
        <Srcimg>rely</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>21</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Hardly</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈhɑːrdli/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>hầu như không</Nghia>
        <YNghia>HÁT LÌ lợm như vậy mà Tuấn hầu như không có quà.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>almost no; almost not; almost none</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>He hardly studies,so his grades aren't good</Eg>
        <Dich>Anh ấy hầu như không học nên điểm của anh ấy không tốt</Dich>
        <Srcimg>hardly</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>22</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Hill</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/hɪl/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>đồi</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Gió đìu HIU thôi qua ngọn đồi .</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>an area of land that is higher than the land around it</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>There are many hills in central VN</Eg>
        <Dich>Có nhiều đồi ở miền Trung Việt Nam</Dich>
        <Srcimg>hill</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>23</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Valley</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈvæli/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>thung lũng</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Đám VE LÌ lợm mãi không chịu rời khỏi thung lũng.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>enlarge image an area of low land between hills or mountains, often with a river flowing through it; the land that a river flows through</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>BacSon valley is a beautiful area surrounded by mountains</Eg>
        <Dich>Thung lũng BacSon là một khu vực tuyệt đẹp được bao quanh bởi các dãy núi</Dich>
        <Srcimg>valley</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>24</ID>
        <ChuDe>Country life and Nature 1</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Nature</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈneɪtʃər/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>thiên nhiên</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Người nào người NẤY CHỜ đợi thiên nhiên được bảo tồn.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>all the plants, animals and things that exist in the universe that are not made by people</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Nature typically has its own to stay alive</Eg>
        <Dich>Thiên nhiên thường có cái riêng để tồn tại</Dich>
        <Srcimg>nature</Srcimg>
    </Item>

</Word>

