<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Word>
    <Item>
        <ID>1</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Marriage </TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈmærɪdʒ/ </PhienAm>
        <Nghia>hôn nhân</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Hôn nhân đang ở bờ MÉ, DỊCH chút nữa là rơi </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>the legal relationship between two people who are married to each other</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Marriages is something that often Scares men </Eg>
        <Dich>Kết hôn là điều thường khiến đàn ông sợ hãi</Dich>
        <Srcimg>marriage</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>2</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Expect </TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ɪkˈspekt/ </PhienAm>
        <Nghia>mong đợi </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Lợi ÍCH BÁCH mong đợi khi tập gym là có bụng 6 múi </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>to think or believe that something will happen or that somebody will do something</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>I dont Expect my boyfriend to buy me expensive things </Eg>
        <Dich>Tôi không mong bạn trai mua cho tôi những thứ đắt tiền</Dich>
        <Srcimg>expect</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>3</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Rule</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ruːl/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>quy tắc </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Quy tắc RU Là phải hát nhạc đồng dao </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a statement of what may, must or must not be done in a particular situation or when playing a game</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>My girlfriend's first rule is that she is always right </Eg>
        <Dich>Quy tắc đầu tiên của bạn gái tôi là cô ấy luôn đúng</Dich>
        <Srcimg>rule</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>4</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Care </TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ker/ </PhienAm>
        <Nghia>quan tâm </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Mai dùng tất cả sự chú tâm để tìm cái ê-KE </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>the process of caring for somebody/something and providing what they need for their health or protection</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>That kid does everything with care </Eg>
        <Dich>Đứa trẻ đó làm mọi thứ một cách cẩn thận</Dich>
        <Srcimg>care</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>5</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Normal </TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈnɔːrml/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>bình thường </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Nóng bình thường thôi mà NÓ MỒ hôi nhễ nhại </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>typical, usual or ordinary; what you would expect</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>In VN, is driving without a helmet normal </Eg>
        <Dich>Ở VN, lái xe không đội mũ bảo hiểm là bình thường</Dich>
        <Srcimg>normal</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>6</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Respect </TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/rɪˈspekt/ </PhienAm>
        <Nghia>tôn trọng </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Đĩa cà RI BÁCH ăn hêt sạch để tôn trọng người nấu </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a strong feeling of approval of somebody/something because of their good qualities or achievements</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Respecting older people is important in Vietnamese culture </Eg>
        <Dich>Tôn trọng người lớn tuổi là điều quan trọng trong văn hóa Việt Nam</Dich>
        <Srcimg>respect</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>7</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>fair</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/fer/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>công bằng </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Cư dân mạng đòi lại tính công bằng cho PHE bị hại </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>acceptable and appropriate in a particular situation</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>It's not fair if they were able to buy the exam answers </Eg>
        <Dich>Thật không công bằng nếu họ có thể mua đáp án kỳ thi</Dich>
        <Srcimg>fair</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>8</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>strange </TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/streɪndʒ/ </PhienAm>
        <Nghia>kì lạ </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Điều kì lạ là SỜ TRÊN đầu tuấn không có tóc! </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>unusual or surprising, especially in a way that is difficult to understand</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>It's s bit strange to hear a Westerner speaking Vietnamese </Eg>
        <Dich>Hơi lạ khi nghe một người phương Tây nói tiếng Việt</Dich>
        <Srcimg>strange</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>9</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Believe </TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/bɪˈliːv/ </PhienAm>
        <Nghia>tin </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Thu không tin BI, LÍP xe đạp hỏng rồi sao sửa được </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>to feel certain that something is true or that somebody is telling you the truth</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>do you Believe in love at first sight? </Eg>
        <Dich>Bạn có tin vào tình yêu từ cái nhìn đầu tiên?</Dich>
        <Srcimg>believe</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>10</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>angry</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈæŋɡri/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>giận </Nghia>
        <YNghia>đừng tức giận mà nhầm " thức ăn" thành "thức ĂNG", DÌ Hai nhé! </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>having strong feelings about something that you dislike very much or about an unfair situation</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>My girlfriend gets angry if I dont text her </Eg>
        <Dich>Bạn gái tôi sẽ tức giận nếu tôi không nhắn tin cho cô ấy</Dich>
        <Srcimg>angry</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>11</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Taboo</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/təˈbuː/ </PhienAm>
        <Nghia>điều cấm </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Điểu cấm kỵ là để em bé TƠ BÚ bình sữa </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>considered so offensive or embarrassing that people must not mention it</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Making fun of the dead is considered a taboo</Eg>
        <Dich>Làm trò cười cho người chết được coi là điều cấm kỵ</Dich>
        <Srcimg>taboo</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>12</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Difference </TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈdɪfrəns/ </PhienAm>
        <Nghia>sự khác biệt </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Mục ĐÍCH PHƠi DẦN cá ra nắng là để tạo sự khác biệt </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>the way in which somebody/something has changed</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>What's the Difference between banhchung and banhtet, besides the shape? </Eg>
        <Dich>Bánh chưng và bánh tét có gì khác ngoài hình dáng?</Dich>
        <Srcimg>difference</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>13</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Mean </TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/miːn/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>có ý định</Nghia>
        <YNghia>MIN có ý định về que nuôi gà trồng rau hả?</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>to have something as a meaning in the same or another language</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>My teacher meant to give me a 10 on the test</Eg>
        <Dich>Giáo viên của tôi có ý định cho tôi điểm 10 trong bài kiểm tra</Dich>
        <Srcimg>mean</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>14</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Pillar</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈpɪlər/ </PhienAm>
        <Nghia>cột nhà </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Tuấn dựa cột nhà, cắn hạt BÍ, LỜ mọi người </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a large round stone, metal or wooden post that is used to support a bridge, the roof of a building, etc.</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>There's a famous pagoda in Hanoi named "One Pillar Pagoda" </Eg>
        <Dich>Có một ngôi chùa nổi tiếng ở Hà Nội tên là "Chùa Một Cột"</Dich>
        <Srcimg>pillar</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>15</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Shrine</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ʃraɪn/ </PhienAm>
        <Nghia>miếu thờ </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Ở miếu thờ khôgn được SỜ RÁI cá </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>a place where people come to worship because it is connected with a holy person or event</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>There's a small shrine on my high school campus </Eg>
        <Dich>Có một ngôi đền nhỏ trong khuôn viên trường trung học của tôi</Dich>
        <Srcimg>shrine</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>16</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>religion </TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/rɪˈlɪdʒən/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>tôn giáo </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Lý do một số tôn giáo không ăn thịt lợn là GÌ, LÝ DẦN dần biết </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>the belief in the existence of a god or gods, and the activities that are connected with the worship of them </TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Some people dont eat certain foods because of their religion </Eg>
        <Dich>Một số người không ăn một số loại thực phẩm vì tôn giáo của họ</Dich>
        <Srcimg>religion</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>17</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Buddhist</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/ˈbuːdɪst/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>phật tử</Nghia>
        <YNghia>các tiểu phật tử đang ngồi làm BÙ ĐI ÍT bài tập thầy đưa </YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>following or connected with the religion of Buddhism</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Buddhists often go to pagodas at least twice a month </Eg>
        <Dich>Các phật tử thường đi lễ chùa ít nhất 2 lần / tháng</Dich>
        <Srcimg>buddhist</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>18</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Proud </TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/praʊd/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>tự hào </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Bố mẹ tự hào vì nhờ Bé RAO phụ thôi nhưng bé làm rất tốt.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>feeling pleased and satisfied about something that you own or have done, or are connected with</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>I feel proud of VN when we won the final </Eg>
        <Dich>Tôi cảm thấy tự hào về VN khi chúng tôi giành chiến thắng trong trận chung kết</Dich>
        <Srcimg>proud</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>19</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Traditional</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/trəˈdɪʃənl/ </PhienAm>
        <Nghia>truyền thống</Nghia>
        <YNghia>Thấy vy gầy TRƠ ĐI, SƠN NỔ bỏng ngô kiểu truyền thống bổ sức.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>being part of the beliefs, customs or way of life of a particular group of people, that have not changed for a long time</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>We should never lose our traditional values</Eg>
        <Dich>Chúng ta đừng bao giờ đánh mất những giá trị truyền thống của mình </Dich>
        <Srcimg>traditional</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>20</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Surprise</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/sərˈpraɪz/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>bất ngờ</Nghia>
        <YNghia>bà SƠ Bị RÁI cá làm bất ngờ.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>an event, a piece of news, etc. that is unexpected or that happens suddenly</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>She Surprised me when she admitted to stealing</Eg>
        <Dich>Cô ấy làm tôi ngạc nhiên khi cô ấy thừa nhận đã ăn cắp</Dich>
        <Srcimg>surprise</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>21</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Control</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/kənˈtrəʊl/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>điều khiển </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Ti thắc mắc tại sao CẦN TRÂU mới điểu khiển đc lưỡi cày.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>the power to make decisions about how a country, an area, an organization, etc. is run</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>We cant control the weather</Eg>
        <Dich>Chúng tôi không thể kiểm soát thời tiết</Dich>
        <Srcimg>control</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>22</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>avoid</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/əˈvɔɪd/ </PhienAm>
        <Nghia>tránh </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Ơ, VOI biết tránh đường khi tham gia giao thông à?.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>to prevent something bad from happening</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>I try avoid eating fried food because it's bad for my health </Eg>
        <Dich>Tôi cố gắng tránh ăn đồ chiên vì nó không tốt cho sức khỏe của tôi</Dich>
        <Srcimg>avoid</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>23</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Familiar</TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/fəˈmɪliər/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>quen thuộc </Nghia>
        <YNghia>Nhăc tới quán PHỞ MỊ, LY Ở đây lâu nên rất quen thuộc rồi.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>well known to you; often seen or heard and therefore easy to recognize</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>Fish sauce is a Familiar seasoning to just about every Vietnamese person</Eg>
        <Dich>Nước mắm là một loại gia vị quen thuộc đối với mỗi người dân Việt Nam</Dich>
        <Srcimg>familiar</Srcimg>
    </Item>
    <Item>
        <ID>24</ID>
        <ChuDe>Holidays and Cultures 2</ChuDe>
        <TuVung>Persuade </TuVung>
        <PhienAm>/pərˈsweɪd/</PhienAm>
        <Nghia>thuyết phục</Nghia>
        <YNghia>BƠ SIẾT CHặt tay thuyết phục mẹ cho nuôi mèo.</YNghia>
        <TiengAnh>to make somebody do something by giving them good reasons for doing it</TiengAnh>
        <Eg>I tried to persuade my parents to believe in me. </Eg>
        <Dich>Tôi đã cố gắng thuyết phục bố mẹ tin tưởng vào tôi.</Dich>
        <Srcimg>persuade</Srcimg>
    </Item>
</Word>

